影城新闻正在播出"冒险聚焦"节目
Movietown News presents Spotlight on Adventure.
您正在收看的
What you are now witnessing
是文明社会未曾见过的影像
is footage never before seen by civilized humanity,
南美洲的一处失落之地
a lost world in South America.
它潜藏在壮丽的天堂瀑布之下
Lurking in the shadow of majestic Paradise Falls,
孕育着尚未被发现的动植物
it sports plants and animals undiscovered by science.
敢问有谁能踏入这偏远之地呢?
Who would dare set foot on this inhospitable summit?
所以 有请今天的主角 查尔斯.蒙兹!
Why, oursubject today, Charles Muntz!
我们敬爱的探险家 他的"冒险精神"号飞船
The beloved explorer lands his dirigible, the Sp rt of Adventure,
于本州降落在新罕布什尔州
in New Hampshire this week,
为期一年的远征得以完成
completing a yearlong expedition to the lost world
这艘轻便的飞艇由蒙兹本人设计
This lighter-than-air craft was designed by Muntz himself
它比22辆头尾相连的警车还长
and is longer than 22 prohibltion paddy wagons placed end to end.
现在有请我们的冒险家出场
And here comes the adventurer now
他与他忠心的狗群形影不离
Never apart from his faithful dogs,
飞船的设计甚至考虑到了犬类的舒适
Muntz conceived the craft forcanine comfort
它是座名副其实的空中宫殿
It's a veritable floating palace in the sky,
设有犬类梳洗和自动跑步设备
complete with doggy bath and mechanical canlne walker
当地人视蒙兹为精神偶像
And, Jiminy Cricket, do the locals consider Muntz the bee's knees
并将他奉为上宾
And how!
去冒险吧!
Adventure Is out there!
蒙兹这次又带回了什么?
But what has Muntz brought back this time?
先生们 我带来了天堂瀑布的怪兽!
Gentlemen, I give you the monsterof Paradise Falls!
天呐 好一只庞然大物!
And, golly, what a swell monster this is!
但这是什么动物呢? 科学家们连声称假
But what's this? Scientists cry foul
国家冒险协会指责蒙兹伪造骨架
The National Explorer's Society accuses Muntz
of fabricating the skeleton
不!
No!
蒙兹被协会除名
The organization strips Muntz
of his membership
蒙受巨大羞辱的蒙兹 发誓将重返天堂瀑布
Humiliated, Muntz vows a return to Paradise Falls
并承诺将活捉此怪兽!
and promises to capture the beast alive!
我保证会活捉怪兽
I promise to capture the beast alive,
如果做不到就永世不回来!
and I will not come back until I do!
就这样 我们的冒险家 再次启程以正其名
And so, the explorer's off to clear his name
一路顺风 查尔斯.蒙兹
Bon voyage, Charles Muntz,
祝你活捉天堂瀑布的怪兽!
and good luck capturing the monsterof Paradise Falls!
查尔斯.蒙兹在此
Here's Charles Muntz
驾着他著名的飞艇
piloting his famous dirigible
他跨越了派克峰
He hurdles Pikes Peak
他跨越了大峡谷
He hurdles the Grand Canyon
他跨越了珠穆朗玛峰
He hurdles Mount Everest
他绕过了珠穆朗玛峰
He goes around Mount Everest
还有他做不到的事吗?
Is there nothing he cannot do?
片名: 飞屋环游记
正如蒙兹本人所说 "去 "
Yes, as Muntz himself says, ''Adventure is''
去冒险吧! 小心了!
Adventure s out there! Look out!
是总统山! 没法打右舷!
Mount Rushmore! Hard to starboard!
必须让"冒险精神"号穿越总统山!
Must get Spirit of Adventure over Mount Rushmore!
挺住 伙计 我的狗狗如何了?
Hold together, old g r How're my dogs doing?
启动所有引擎! 让我们升到26000英尺的高空吧
A engines ahead full! Let's take her up to 26,000 feet.
向南转舵18度
Rudders 18 degrees towards the south
天气真好 东风10节
It's a beautiful day Winds out of the east at 10 knots
能见度  极高 将天气情况记录进航行日志
Visibility unlimited Enterthe weather in the logbook.
哦! 下方有发现 我要把它带回去研究
Oh! Theres something down there I wi brng it back for science
喔! 是只小狗! 啊 没时间了! 有风暴! 闪电冰雹同时来袭!
Aw! Its a puppy! Ah No time! A storm! Lightn ng Hail.
- 你在这干嘛? - 啊!
- What are you doing? - Ahhh!
你不知道这里是高级会所吗?
Don't you know this is an exclusive club?
只有冒险家能进来
Only explorers get in here,
不是什么带头盔和风镜的 街头小毛孩想进就能进的
not just any k d off the street with a helmet and a pair of goggles.
你以为这样就能混进来吗? 是不是?
Do you th nk you've got what it takes? Well, do you?
好吧 欢迎加入
All right, you're n Welcome aboard
怎么了? 哑巴吗?
What's wrong? Can't you talk?
嘿 我不咬人的
Hey, I dont bite
我们是一伙的了
You and me, we're in a club now
我看到你的气球飞走了 我们去取吧
I saw where your balloon went Come on Lets go get it.
我叫爱丽
My names Ellie
在那儿呢
There it is
往前走啊
Well, go ahead
去啊
Go on.
喔
Ow.
嗨 小子!
Hey, kid!
我觉得你可能需要点鼓励
Thought you m ght need a litt e cheering up.
我有些东西要给你看看
I got something to show you
一会儿你要看的东西
I am about to let you see something
我以前从没给别人看过
I have never shown to another human being.
这辈子从没有过!
Ever! In my life!
你得发誓不会告诉别人
You'll have to swear you wil not tell anyone.
划十字 快!
Cross your heart Do it!
我的冒险之书
My Adventure Book
你认识他的
You know him
查尔斯.蒙兹 大冒险家
Charles Muntz, explorer
等我长大了 要去他去的地方
When I get big, I'm going where he's going,
南美洲 和美洲差不多但在更南边
South Amerca It's like America but south
想知道我会住哪吗?
Wanna know where I'm gonna live?
"天堂瀑布 失落的世界"
''Paradise Falls, a and lost in time''
我从图书馆的书上撕下来的
I ripped this right out of a I brary book
我要把我的会所搬到那儿 就安在瀑布的旁边
I'm gonna move my clubhouse there and park it right next to the falls.
一旦我到了那儿
Who knows what ives up there
谁知道有什么在等着我呢?
And once I get there?
我把后面的空页留给以后的冒险
Wel , I'm saving these pages for al the adventures I'm gonna have.
只是我不知道该怎么去天堂瀑布
Only ljust don't know how I m gonna get to Parad se Falls
没错! 你会开小飞船送我去!
That's t You can take us there in a blimp!
划十字! 发誓你会做到!
Swear you' take us Cross your heart!
快! 划十字! 好 你答应了 不能反悔哦
Cross it! Cross your heart! Good you promised No backing out
那明儿见了 小子 再见!
Well, see you tomorrow, k d Bye!
去冒险吧!
Adventure s out there!
你不怎么说话啊
You know, you don't ta k very much
我喜欢!
I like you!
喔
Wow
哈!
Hah!
史蒂文 别跟我闹了!
Stevie, throw me a deuce!
挺壮观的哈 爱丽?
Quite a sight, huh, Ellie?
啊 信来了
Uh Mails here
荫树橡木疗养院 乖乖
Shady Oaks Ret rement Oh brother
唔
Hmm
早啊 弗雷德里克森先生 需要帮忙吗?
Hey Morning Mr Fredricksen Need any help there?
不用 噢 对了!
No Yes!
告诉你们那位老板 你们这些家伙在毁我的房子
Te I your boss overthere that you boys are ruining our house.
跟您说一声
Well, just to let you know,
我老板很愿意接手您的老房子
my boss w I be happy to take this o d place off your hands,
并且比上次的出价还高一倍!
and for double h s last offer!
您觉得如何?
What do you say to that?
呃 这应该是"不"了哈?
Uh, I take that as a ' no,'' then?
我已经和你们老板说得很清楚了
I believe I made my pos tion to your boss qute clear
您把李子汁倒进了他汽车的油箱
You poured prune ju ce in his gas tank
是的 那感觉挺好 来 让我和他说说
Yeah, that was good. Here, et me ta k to him
穿西装的那个 没错 就是你 好好洗洗 臭虫!
You in the suit Yes, you. Take a bath, hippie!
我不是他的同伙!
I am not with hlm!
这不是闹着玩的 他会想法设法得到您的房子
Th s is serious He's out to get your house.
告诉你老板他能得到这房子
Tel your boss he can have our house
- 真的? - 那也是我死了之后!
- Really? - When I m dead!
我当您说了"也许"
I'll take that as a maybe
现在订购 你能获得相机
Order now, you get the camera,
还能获得打印机 4倍光学变焦
you get the printer, 4x optical zoom,
施耐德镜头 照片打印 SD卡
Schneider lens, photo printer, SD card
"下午好 我叫罗素"
''Good afternoon My name is Russell
"我是一名野外探险队员 隶属于54团第12小分队"
''And I am a Wi derness Explorer in Trbe 54, Sweat Lodge 12
"您今天需要什么帮助吗 先生?"
'Are you in need of any ass stance today sir?''
不用
No
- 我能帮您过马路 - 不用
-I could help you cross the street -No
- 我能帮您过院子 - 不用
-I could help you cross youryard -No
- 我能帮您过门廊 - 不用
-I could help you cross your porch - No
我总得帮你过点什么
Well, I gotta help you cross something
不用 我好得很
No I m doing fine
"下午好 我的名字是罗素"
''Good afternoon My name is Russell''
- 孩子 孩子 - "我是一名野外探险队员"
- Kid Kd -''And I am a Wilderness Explorer
- "隶属于54团第12小分队" - 我  别说了 孩子!
-''in Tribe 54 Sweat Lodge 12'' - I Slow down Kid!
- "今天您需要什么 " - 谢谢
-''Are you n need of any assistance'' -Thank you,
- 但我不需要任何帮助! - " .帮助吗 先生?"
-but I don't need any help! -' ...today, sir?''
说吧
Proceed
- "下午好" - 跳到最后吧!
- 'Good afternoon'' -But skip to the end!
看到这些了吗? 这些是我野外探险的徽章
See these? These are my Wilderness Explorer badges
你可能注意到少了一枚 那是帮助老人的徽章
You may notice one s m ssing It's my Assisting the Elderly badge.
如果拿到了 我就能成为高级野外探险队员了
If I get it, I will become a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
"野外探险去啊!"
''The wlderness must be explored!''
嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw Raar!
那样就太棒了! 会有个表彰大会
It's gonna be great! There's a big ceremony,
老爸们都会去 并给我们别上徽章
and all the dads come and they p n on our badges.
所以说你想帮助老人家?
So, you want to assist an old person?
是的! 这样我就能升高级了
Yep! Then I' be a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
- 你听说过沙锥鸟吗? - 沙锥鸟?
-You ever heard of a snipe? - Snipe?
一种鸟 眼睛小而圆
Bird Beady eyes
每晚都溜进我的院子偷吃杜鹃花
Every night it sneaks in my yard and gobbles my poor azaleas.
我又老又弱 抓不到它 如果有人能帮我就好了
I'm elderly and nfrm I can't catch it If on y someone cou d help me.
- 我! 我! 我帮您! - 不知你行吗 它可狡猾着呢
- Me me! I' I do it! -I don't know It's awfully crafty.
你得拍三次手才能引它出来
You'd have to cap your hands three times to lure it in
我会找到的 弗雷德里克森先生!
I'll find him Mr Fredricksen!
向下过两条街就是它的洞了 如果你向下走
I think its burrow is two blocks down If you go past
过两条街 知道了 沙锥鸟
Two blocks down Got t Snipe
过来吧 小鸟儿 小鸟儿
Here, snipey snipey
找到了记得带到这里来
Bring it back here when you find it
沙锥鸟!
Snipe!
好了 再向前 向前
Okay, keep her coming Keep coming
停 停 停!
And stop Stop Stop!
怎么 嘿! 嘿! 你!
Why Hey Hey you!
你在干什么呢?
What do you What do you think you re doing?
- 很抱歉 先生 - 别碰这个
-I am so sorry sir - Don't touch that
不 不 不 我会帮您修好的
No, no, no Let me take care of that for you.
- 离我的邮箱远点! - 嗨 先生 我
-Get away from our mailbox! - Hey Sir, I.
你别碰它!
I don't want you to touch it!
噢!
Ow!
史蒂夫 你还好吗?
Steve, you all right?
抱歉 弗雷德里克森先生
Sorry, Mr Fredricksen
我觉得你并不像个危险人物 拿着
You don't seem like a public menace to me. Take this.
荫树橡木的工作人员 明早会来接您的 好吗?
The guys from Shady Oaks will be by to pick you up in the morn ng, okay?
现在该怎么办呢 爱丽?
What do I do now, Ellie?
早啊 先生们
Morning, gentlemen
早安 弗雷德里克森先生 准备好走了吗?
Good morn ng, Mr Fredricksen You ready to go?
准备得不能再准备了
Ready as I' ever be
能帮我拿下这个吗?
Would you do me a favor and take this?
我们一会儿在车上见
I'll meet you at the van in just a minute
我得好好和老房子告别
I wanna say one ast goodbye to the old place.
当然了 您慢慢来吧
Sure Take a I the time you need sir
见得多了 他可能要去上第80次厕所
That's typical He's probab y going to the bathroom forthe 80th time.
他真该好好收拾收拾呢
You think he'd take better care of his house
永别了 小子们! 我会在天堂瀑布给你们寄明信片的
So long, boys! I'I send you a postcard from Paradise Fal s
耶!
Heh!
我们上路了 爱丽
Were on ourway, Ellie
呃?
Huh?
哼
Hmm
你好 弗雷德里克森先生 是我 罗素
Hi Mr Fredricksen It's me, Russell
你在外头做什么 孩子?
What are you doing out here, kid?
我找到了沙锥鸟 跟着它到了您门廊下
I found the snipe and I followed it under your porch,
但沙锥鸟有条长尾巴 更像只大老鼠
but th s snipe had a ong tail and looked more like a large mouse.
请让我进去吧
Please let me in
不行
No
哦 好吧 你可以进
Oh alright, you can come
来
in
呃
Huh
我从没坐过会飞的屋子
I've never been in a floatng house before.
风镜啊 看看这玩意 哇哦! 您要去旅行吗?
Goggles Look at th s stuff Wow! You're going on a trip?
"天堂瀑布 失落的世界"
''Paradise Falls, a and lost in time''
您要去南美洲啊 弗雷德里克森先生?
You're going to South America, Mr Fredricksen?
别碰那个! 你会弄脏它的
Don't touch that! You'I soil it
大多数人会坐飞机
You know most people take a plane,
但您很聪明 因为这样您能带齐 电视 餐具和所有的东西
but you re smart because you will have al your TV and cocks and stuff.
哇 您是这样驾驶房子的?
Whoa Is this how you steer your house?
真的管用吗?
Does it really work?
小孩 你别去碰
Kid would you stop with the
- 这样右转 - 不要动
-This makes it go right -Let go of that...
- 这样就转左了 - 快住手
-And that way's left - Knock it off
嘿 快看! 高楼大厦
Hey, look! Bui dings
那楼离这么近 我都能碰到了
That bu Iding's so close I cou d almost touch it
哇! 真棒!
Wow! This is great!
您也该来试试 弗雷德里克森先生
You shou d try th s Mr Fredricksen
看啊 下面的公车站能送我回家 过两条街就到!
Look, there's a bus that could take me home two blocks away!
嘿 这里能看到您的房子
Hey I can see your house from here
- 别乱动了 小孩 - 哇哦!
Don't jerk around so much, kid Whoa!
这办法恐怕不行
Well, that's not gonna work
我认识那云 是积雨云
I know that coud lts a cumulonimbus
您知道吗
Did you know that
当暖气流升到冷气流上面
the cumulonimbus forms
就会形成积雨云了?
when warm air rises over cool air?
整晚充气球为了什么啊?
Stayed up al n ght blowing up balloonsforwhat?
所以就形成了闪电
and that's how we get lightning
- 说得好 孩子 - 弗雷德里克森先生?
-That's nice kid -Mr Fredricksen?
暴风雨要来了 越来越吓人了
Theres a storm coming It's starting to get scary.
我们要被吹散了! 我们有大麻烦了!
We're gonna get b own to b ts! We're in big trouble..
- 你在那儿干嘛呢? - 快看
-What are you doing over there? - Look
看到了吗? 积雨云
See? Cumulonimbus.
我的背包!
My pack!
抓到了!
Got ya!
我还以为您死了呢
I thought you were dead
出什么事了?
What happened?
我刚在掌舵 我做到了 我能驾驭飞屋了
I steered us I did I steered the house
掌舵?
Steered us?
您把东西抱紧后就睡着了
After you tied your stuff down, you took a nap.
所以我就跑前面掌舵 我们就到了这里
So I went ahead and steered us down here
那是
Yeah. Sure.
我们迷路了
Can't tell where we are.
哦 我们已经在南美了
Oh we're in South Amerca all right
有了我的野外探险GPS 小菜一碟
It was a cinch with my Wilderness Explorer GPS.
- GP什么? - 我爸给我的
-GP What? -My dad gave it to me
它能指示我们目前的所在地
It shows exacty where we are on the planet.
有了这宝贝 我们永远不会迷路!
With this baby, we'll never be ost!
哎呀
Oops
放你下去 坐公车回家吧
Well get you down, find a bus stop,
你就说要回去找妈妈
you just tell the man you wanna go back to your mother.
当然 但我觉得天堂瀑布没公车吧
Sure, but I don't think they have buses in Parad se Falls
好了 这样就行了
There That ought to do it
我再给你些零钱坐车
Here I'll g ve you some change for bus fare.
不用了 我可以用公交卡
No, I'll just use my city bus pass
喔 那得转个无数站
Whoa That's gonna be like a bill on transfers
才能到我家了
to get back to my house
弗雷德里克森先生 要多久着陆啊?
Mr Fredrcksen, how much longer?
我们升得挺高的 要花个几小时着落吧
We I we're up pretty high Oould take hours to get down.
那是楼房之类的吧
That th ng was building or something
那是什么 弗雷德里克森先生?
What was that, Mr Fredricksen?
我们应该还没到地吧
We can't be cose to the ground yet
等等! 等等 不 不要! 不要 不要!
Wait! Wa t, no don't! Don't don't!
等等 等等!
Wait, wait Wait!
- 罗素 坚持住 - 哇哦!
- Russell, hang on Hey - Whoa Whoa!
啊啊啊啊啊!
Aaaagggghhhhh!
- 往回走 往回走 - 好的
- Walk back Walk back - Okay
加油 加油
Come on Come on.
我们  在哪儿呢?
Where Where are we?
这里不像是城市或丛林 弗雷德里克森先生
This doesn't look I ke the city orthe jung e, Mr. Fredricksen.
别担心 爱丽 我抓住了
Don't worry Ell e I got it
瞧那儿
There t is
爱丽 真是太漂亮了
Ellie, it's so beautiful
我们成功了
We made it
成功了! 罗素 我们能飞到那儿! 快爬上去 爬上去!
We made it! Russe We could float right overthere! Climb up. C mb up!
你是说 帮助您?
You mean, assist you?
- 是的 是的 随便啦 - 好的 我这就爬
-Yeah yeah Whatever - Okay. I'll climb up
- 看着点! - 抱歉
- Watch it! - Sorry
等你上去了 再把我吊上去!
Now, when you get up there, go ahead and ho st me up!
知道了吗?
Got it?
你到门廊了吗?
You on the porch yet?
什么? 就这样了?
What? That's it?
我好不容易到了这儿 结果被困在这堆石头上了?
I came a I this way just to get stuck at the wrong end of this rock pile?
好极了
Great.
嘿 如果我帮您过去 你能来签发我的徽章吗?
Hey, f I could assist you overthere, would you sign off on my badge?
- 你在说什么? - 我们能拖着房子去瀑布
- What are you talk ng about? -We could wa k your house to the falls.
- 拖着去? - 是啊! 我们已经稳住它了
- Walk it? -Yeah! After al , we weigh it down.
可以像拖气球一样拖着走
We could walk it right overthere Like a parade balloon
现在我们就快速而安静地 拖着房子去瀑布吧
Now, we're gonna walk to the falls quickly and quietly
- 不要饶舌音乐或闪电舞 - 好的
- with no rap music orflashdancing - Uh-huh
我们最多有三天时间 不然气球里的氦气就漏光了
We have three days, at best before the helium leaks out of those ba loons
如果没到之前就没气的话
And if were not at the falls when that happens
- 沙子 - 我们就到不了瀑布
- Sand - we're not gettng to the falls
我找沙子了!
I found sand!
别担心 爱丽 我们会把房子安在那儿的
Don't you worry El ie We'll get our house overthere.
是不是觉得有趣了?
Th s is fun already isn t it?
等我们到了那里 您一定倍感受助于人
By the tme we get there you're gonna feel so assisted.
哦 弗雷德里克森先生 如果我们不巧走散的话
Oh, Mr Fredricksen if we happen to get separated,
用野外探险专用呼叫法
use the W derness Explorer call
嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw Raar!
等等 再问一句 我们为啥去天堂瀑布来着?
Wa t Why are we going to Parad se Falls again?
嘿 我们来玩个游戏
Hey lets play a game
叫做"看看谁安静的时间更长"
It's called ''see who can be qu et the longest.''
酷! 我妈也爱玩这游戏!
Cool! My mom oves that game!
破玩意儿!
Darn thing!
快点 罗素 你能不能快点?
Come on Russe Would you hurry it up?
我累死了 膝盖好痛
I'm tired And my knee hurts
哪个膝盖?
Which knee?
我的手肘也好痛 而且我得上厕所了
My elbow hurts and I have to go to the bathroom.
我五分钟前才问过你
I asked you about that five minutes ago
我那时确实不想嘛!
Wel , I didn't have to go then!
我不想再走了 能停下么?
I don't wanna walk anymore. Can we stop?
罗素 你再不快点 老虎就会来吃了你的
Russell, if you don't hurry up, the tigers wll eat you
南美洲没有老虎 动物学常识
There are no tigers n South America Zoology
噢 看在老天的份上 到灌木丛里解决掉吧
Oh forthe love of Pete! Go on nto the bushes and do your bus ness.
好 给你! 看好我的东西
Okay Here! Hold my stuff
我老早就想试试了
I've always wanted to try this
弗雷德里克森先生
Mr Fredricksen,
我应该先挖坑还是后挖啊?
am I supposed to dig the ho e before or after?
我可不管!
None of my concern!
噢 该先挖的!
Oh. It's before!
噢! 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦!
Bah! La la la la a!
嗯?
Huh?
脚印?
Tracks?
沙锥鸟
Sn pe
过来 沙锥鸟 出来啊 沙锥鸟
Here, snipe Come on out snipe
沙锥鸟
Sn pe
嗯?
Huh?
哈 找到你了! 别怕 小鸟儿
Ha Gotcha! Don t be afraid, ltt e snipe
我是野外探险家 我是大自然的好朋友
I am a Wilderness Explorer, so I'm a friend to all of nature
还想吃么?
Want some more?
乖乖 别都吃光了 出来吧
Hi, boy Don't eat it all Come on out
出来吧 出来吧 别怕 小鸟儿
Come on Come on Don't be afraid, litt e snipe
乖乖 可爱的小鸟儿 可爱的
Nice snipe Good little snipe Nice
大鸟
Giant snipe
- 我发现沙锥鸟了! - 噢! 是吗!
-I found the snipe! - Oh! D d you?
- 它们是不是很高? - 噢 没错 它们确实很高
- Are they ta I? - Oh, yes, theyre very tall.
- 是不是五颜六色的? - 没错!
-Do they have a lot of colors? - They do indeed!
- 它们是不是喜欢吃巧克力? - 噢 是啊  巧克力?
-Do they ike chocolate? - Oh yes... choco ate?
- 噢! 那是什么东西? - 这是沙锥鸟!
-Gah! What is that thing? -It's a snipe!
世上没有沙锥鸟这东西!
There's no such thing as a snipe!
- 但你说沙锥鸟吃了你的  噢! - 嘿
-But you said snipes eat your Whoa! - Hey
嘿! 快滚开! 嘿!
Go on! Get out of here! Go on!
噢!
Whoa!
当心 罗素!
Careful Russe I!
嘿 看啊 弗雷德里克森先生 它喜欢我 喔!
Hey, look, Mr Fredricksen It likes me Whoa!
- 罗素 - 噢 别挠了! 好痒
- Russel -No, stop! That t ckles.
快走开! 走开! 走!
Get out of here Go on! Get!
噢 不 不 不! 凯文! 没事的 弗雷德里克森先生是好人
Uh- oh No, no no! Kevin! It's okay. Mr. Fredrcksen s nice.
- 凯文? - 我刚给它取的名字
- Kevin? -Yeah That's h s name I just gave him.
走开! 听到没! 快走! 嘿! 那是我的!
Beat it! Vamoose! Scram! Hey! Thats mine!
走! 走! 快滚开!
Shoo! Shoo Get out of here!
快! 快走吧!
Go on! Beat it!
我能留下它吗? 求求你了?
Can we keep him? Please?
我来喂它 陪它散步 我会打理它的麻烦事的
I'll get the food for him I'I walk him I'll change h s newspapers
不
No.
无论树木鱼儿或鼹鼠 都是探险家的好朋友
An Exp orer s a friend to all, be it plants orfish or tiny mole''
- 狗屁不通 - 就是通的
-That doesn t even rhyme. -Yeah it does
- 嘿 快看 凯文 - 什么?
-Hey, ook Kevin -What?
给我下来! 不准上去!
Get down! You re not allowed up there!
你马上给我下来!
You come down here right now!
老天!
Sheesh!
你能相信吗 爱丽?
Can you believe this, Ellie?
爱丽?
Ellie?
嘿 爱丽! 我能养这只鸟吗?
Hey, Ellie! Could I keep the bird?
唔 唔
Uh- huh. Uh-huh.
她要我跟你说可以
She said for you to let me
但是我跟他说不行 我跟你说了不行!
But I told h m no I told you no!
不 行
N- O.
我看到你了
I see you back there
快走! 回你该去的地方! 去烦烦别人饶了我们吧
Go on! Get out of here Shoo! Go annoy someone else for a while
嘿 那边的人 你们还好吗?
Hey, are you okay over there?
恩 你好?
Uh Hello?
噢!
Oh!
你好 先生! 谢天谢地
Hello, sir! Thank goodness
能在这儿碰到人真是太好了
Its nice to know someone else is up here.
我能闻到你们
I can smell you
什么? 你能闻到我们?
What? You can smell us?
我能闻到你们
I can smell you
嗨
Hey
你在跟石头说话
You were talking to a rock
嘿 那块看起来像只海龟
Hey, that one looks like a turtle
快看那块! 像只狗
Look at that one! That one looks like a dog.
- 真的是只狗狗! - 什么?
-It s a dog! -What?
我家不允许养狗
Were not allowed to have dogs n my apartment
嘿 我喜欢狗狗
Hey, I like dogs
你狗在我们这儿!
We have your dog!
- 喔! - 这是谁家的狗?
-Whoa! -Wonderwho he be ongs to.
坐下 乖狗狗 快看 他受过训练 握手
Sit, boy Hey, ook, he's tra ned Shake
Uh- huh
- 说话 - 嗨 你好
-Speak -Hi, there
这狗刚刚是不是说 "嗨 你好"?
Did that dog just say ''Hi, there''?
恩 是的
Oh yes
我叫道格 我对你一见钟情
My name is Dug I have just met you, and I love you.
我主人给我做了这个项圈 他人很好也很聪明
My master made me th s collar He is a good and smart master,
他给我装了项圈 我就能说话了 有松鼠
and he made me this co lar so that I may talk. Squirre
我主人人好又聪明
My master is good and smart
不可能
It's not possible
噢 当然可能 因为我主人很聪明
Oh, it is,because my master is smart
- 太酷了 这是做什么用的? - 嘿 你能不能
-Coo What do these do, boy? -Hey, would you
我用这个项圈
I use that collar...
跟别人交流 请你住手吧
to talk wth I wou d be happy if you stopped.
罗素 不要碰那东西! 可能有辐射啥的!
Russell don't touch that! It could be radioactve or something!
我是个追踪高手
I am a great tracker
我的同伴派我来独立执行 一项特殊的任务
My pack sent me on a specia mission all by myself.
你们见过一只鸟吗?
Have you seen a bird?
我的任务就是来找它 我追踪气味到了这里
I want to find one, and I've been on the scent
我是个追踪高手 我之前向你们提过吗?
I am a great tracker Did I mention that?
嘿 就是这只鸟
Hey, that s the bird
我从未这么近距离看过 但没错就是它了
I have never seen one up close, but th s is the bird
我能把你的鸟作为俘虏 押回营地吗?
May I take your bird back to camp as my prsoner?
好 好 带走吧 路上顺便学学 真正的狗是怎么叫的
Yes, yes, take t And on the way, earn how to bark I ke a rea dog.
我会狗叫
I can bark.
还有嚎叫
And heres howling
我们能留下它吗? 求你了 求你了 求求你了!
Can we keep him? Please, please, p ease!
- 不行 - 但它是只会说话的狗诶!
-No -But t's a talking dog!
这肯定是什么鬼把戏 我们继续朝瀑布进发吧
It's just a weird trick orsomething Let's get to the fal s
请做我的俘虏吧
Please be my prisoner
噢 求你了 噢 求你做我的俘虏吧!
Oh please, oh, please be my prisoner!
噢! 就是这儿了 我闻到那只鸟的气味了!
Oh! Here it is I picked up the bird's scent!
等一下 等一下 这是什么?
Wait a minute, wait a minute! What is th s?
巧克力 我闻到巧克力的气味
Chocolate. I sme chocolate.
我闻到李子和假牙的气味! 这都是些什么人?
I'm gettng prunes and denture cream! Who are they?
噢 伙计 主人不会满意的
Oh, man, Masterwill not be pleased
我们最好向他报告 有人抓住那鸟了 对吗 老大?
We betterte him someone took the bird. R ght, Alpha?
不
No
很快我们就会抓到那只鸟的
Soon enough the bird will be ours yet again
继续追踪气味 我的朋友
Find the scent, my compadres,
没有功劳也有苦劳嘛
and you too shall have much rewardings
主人会多给一点奖赏的
from Masterforthe toil factor you wage.
嘿 老大 你的项圈好像有点问题
Hey, Alpha, I think there's something wrong with your collar.
你肯定撞到它了
You mustve bumped it
没错 你的声音听起来真滑稽!
Yeah, your vo ce sounds funny!
老二! 老三! 或许你们想要  松鼠!
Beta! Gamma! Mayhaps you desire to Squirrel!
或许你们想挑战一下我的权威
ALPHA: Mayhaps you deslre to challenge the ranking
这排位可是凭着 我的力量与智慧获得的
that I have been assigned by my strength and cunning.
不 不 不 不过道格或许想试试 你可以问问他
No, no, no But maybe Dug wou d. You might wanna ask him.
我想他正在执行特别任务 找那个大鸟呢吧
Yeah I wonder fhe's found the b rd on h s very specia mission
别哪壶不开提哪壶
Do not mention Dug to me at thls time
这愚蠢的任务够他忙活的了
His fool's errand will keep him most occupied Most occupied indeed.
你们难道不同意我的看法吗?
Do you not agree with that which I am saying to you now?
当然同意 可一旦主人发现 你让道格单独行动
Sure, but the second Master finds out you sent Dug out by himself,
我们都没好果子吃
none of us will get a treat
你们都是聪明的家伙 我可靠的伙伴们
You are wise, my trusted lieutenant.
我是老大 呼叫道格 快回话 道格
This is Alpha calling Dug Come in, Dug.
嘿 老大 你的声音好滑稽
Hi, Alpha Hey, your voice sounds funny
我知道! 我知道! 你见到那只鸟了吗?
I know, I know! Have you seen the bird?
噢 那只鸟已经是我的俘虏了
Why, yes The bird is my prisoner now
哦 很好!
Yeah, rght!
不可能! 你在哪里?
lmpossible! Where are you?
我跟那只鸟在一起
I am here with the blrd,
我会把它带回来的 这样你们就会喜欢我了
and I will bring it back, and then you will like me.
- 得挂了 - 嘿 道格 你在和谁说话呢?
- Gotta go. -Hey, Dug, who you talking to?
- 不 等等 等等! - 道格在干什么?
- No, wait, wait! - What's Dug doing?
他为什么跟一个小男孩在一起?
Why's he with that small mai man?
他们在哪里?
Where are they?
在那儿 我们走!
There he is Come on.!
噢 求你了 噢 求你了 噢 求求你做了我的俘虏吧
Oh, please, oh, please, oh, please be my prisoner
道格 不要再烦凯文了!
Dug, stop bothering Kevin!
那位先生说我可以带走这只鸟
That man there says I can take the bird,
而且我喜欢那位先生 就像喜欢我主人一样
and I love that man there like he is my master.
我才不是你主人!
I am not your master!
我再次警告你 大鸟
I am warning you once aga n, bird
- 嘿! 放开它 - 我跳上来咯 大鸟
-Hey! Quit it -I am jumping on you now bird
罗素 照这个速度 我们永远也到不了瀑布
Russell, at th s rate we'll never get to the falls.
来吧 大鸟
Here bird
我不是谁的主人 听到没?
I am nobody's master, got it?
我不想看到你 我也不想看到你!
I don't want you here, and I don't want you here!
我受够你了!
I'm stuck wth you!
要是我数到3 你俩还没消失
And if you two don't clear out of here by the time I count to three...
球! 噢 伙计 噢 伙计! 球!
A ba I! Oh boy oh boy! A ba I!
球? 你想要这个 狗狗?
Ball? Yeah yeah? You want it, boy?
嗯? 嗯? 耶 耶?
Huh? Huh? Yeah Yeah?
是的 我老早就想要这球了
Yes, I do I do ever so want the ball
- 去捡吧 - 噢 太好了! 噢 太好了!
- Go get t - Oh boy! Oh boy!
我会捡回来的!
I w I get it and then br ng it back!
快点 罗素 给我些巧克力
Quick, Russell Give me some chocolate
- 为什么? - 给我就是了!
- Why? -Just g ve it to me!
大鸟 大鸟!
Bird Bird!
快走 罗素
Come on Russell
等等 等等 弗雷德里克森先生
Wait Wait Mr Fredricksen
我们这是在做什么?
What are we doing?
噢 我们走得够远了 凯文会想我的
Hey, we're pretty far now Kevin's gonna m ss me
我想那招应该奏效了
I think that did the trick
嗨 主人
H , Master
没用
Afternoon
谢谢你让我们躲雨 爱丽
Well, thanks for keeping us dry anyway, Ellie.
哪个是在前面的?
Which one's the front?
噢 孩子
Oh boy
这是第三步还是第五步?
Is this step three or step five?
好了
There.
帮你搭好了
All done Thats for you
噢
Oh...
搭帐篷真难
Tents are hard
你不是超级野外探险家么? 还有那什么GPM和奖章?
Wait Aren't you superwlderness guy, with the GPMs and the badges?
是的 我能告诉你个秘密吗?
Yeah, but can I tell you a secret?
- 不 - 好吧 秘密是
-No -AI right. Here t goes.
我其实从来没搭过帐篷 好了 我说出来了
I neveractualy bu It a tent before. There, I said it
你以前不是野营过吗?
You've been camping before, haven t you?
是的 但是从未在野外
Well, never outside
那你为什么不向你爸爸 讨教讨教怎么搭帐篷?
Well, why didn t you ask your dad how to build a tent?
我想他不会跟我聊这些的
I don't th nk he wants to talk about th s stuff
你不问怎么能知道 也许他比你想得更在行噢
Well, why don t you try him sometime Maybe he' I surprise you.
他总是出差 我不常见到他
Well, he's away a lot I don't see h m much
他总有回家的时候吧
He's gotta be home sometime
我会打电话给他 但菲丽斯说 我这样太打搅他了
Wel , I call, but Phyllis told me I bug him too much.
菲丽斯? 你就这样直呼妈妈的名字
Phyllis? You cal your own mother by her first name?
菲丽斯不是我妈妈
Phyllis isn't my mom
噢
Oh.
但是他保证会来参加 我的探险家授奖仪式
But he promised hed come to my Exp orer ceremony
亲自把助老奖章给我戴上
to pin on my Assist ng the Elderly badge.
到时他就能教我搭帐篷了 对吧?
So, he can show me about tents then, right?
你要不要睡一会?
Hey, why don t you get some sleep?
我可不想吵醒这些 逃亡的马戏团成员
Don't wanna wake up the traveling f ea circus.
弗雷德里克森先生?
Mr Fredricksen?
道格说他要抓凯文做俘虏
Dug says he wants to take Kev n prisoner.
我们得保护它
We have to protect him
凯文能跟我们一起走吗?
Can Kevin go with us?
好吧 它可以
All rght, he can come
保证你不会丢下它?
Promise you won t leave h m?
- 好的 - 划十字?
-Yeah -Cross your heart?
划十字
Cross my heart
我这是招谁惹谁了我 爱丽?
What have I got myself into, Ellie?
早安 甜心
Morning, sweetheart
我们得快点了
We better get moving
大鸟走了
Bird's gone
也许罗素不会注意到 好咧 大家都起床吧!
Maybe Russell won't notice All right, everybody up!
凯文呢? 他不见了! 凯文! 道格 快去找凯文!
Wheres Kevin? Hes wandered off! Kevin! Dug, f nd Kevin!
找鸟 找鸟! 这儿!
Find the bird, fnd the bird! Hi hi Po nt!
瞧 它在那里!
Look There he s!
那儿!
Point!
嘿 那是我的食物! 给我从屋顶上下来!
Hey That's my food! Get off my roof!
对 从屋顶上下来
Yeah get off of his
它在干什么?
What is it doing?
那只鸟在回应她的孩子
The bird is cal ng to her babies
她的孩子
Her babies
凯文是女的?
Kevin s a girl?
她的家在那边的乱石林里
Her house s overthere in those twisty rocks
她是出来给孩子找食物的 现在得回去喂它们了
She has been gathering food for her babies and must get back to them
等一下 凯文要走了?
Wait Kevins just leaving?
你答应过要保护她的
But you prom sed to protect her
她的孩子需要她 我们得让他们团聚!
Her babies need her We gotta make sure they're together!
抱歉 罗素 我们已经耽误太多时间了
Sorry Russe Weve lost enough t me already
Yeah
这是她最喜欢的巧克力
Th s was her favorte chocolate
因为她走了 所以有多的给你了
Because you sent her away, theres more foryou
啊?
Huh?
凯文?
Kevin?
那只鸟在哪里? 你说你抓到那只鸟了
Where's the bird? You said you had the bird.
噢 没错 噢 没错
Oh, yes Oh yes
既然我这么说了 我知道你现在会怎么想
Since I have said that, I can see how you would think that
- 它在哪里? - 嗯 明天
- Where is it? - Uh Tomorrow
明天再来 到时那只鸟就又是我的了
Come back tomorrow, and then I will again have the bird Yes.
你追丢了! 为什么我都不感到吃惊?
You lost it! Why do I not have a surprised feeling?
至少你让我们找到了这个小男孩
Well, at least you now have led us to the small mailman
还有那个闻起来像李子的人
and the one who smells of prunes
我们找到他们 主人定会高兴的
ALPHA: Master will be most pleased we have found them
还会问他们很多问题 走吧!
and will ask of them many questions Come!
等一下 我们才不跟你们走呢! 我们要去瀑布!
Wait We're not going with you! We're going to the falls!
滚开!
Get away from me!
让开
Get down!
停下!
Stay!
你坐那玩意儿来的?
You came here in that?
哦 没错
Uh yeah
一座房子? 一座飞屋?
In a house? A floating house?
这是我见过的最荒谬的事
That s the darnedest thing I've ever seen
你们不是来抓我的鸟的吧?
You're not after my b rd, are you?
但如果你要借点糖之类的
But if you needed to borrow a cup of sugar
我很乐意效劳
I'd be happy to oblige
好了 这都是个误会
Well, th s is al a misunderstanding
我的狗狗们弄错了
My dogs made a mistake
等一下 你是查尔斯.蒙兹?
Wait Are you Charles Muntz?
是的 我就是
Yeah, we I yes
那个查尔斯.蒙兹?
THE Chares Muntz?
"去冒险吧!"
''Adventure is out there!''
真的是他! 那是查尔斯.蒙兹!
It's really him! That's Chares Muntz!
- 真的? 谁是查尔斯.蒙兹? - 他!
-It s? Who's Charles Muntz? - H m!
- 没错! 没错 真是他! - 我是卡尔.弗雷德里克森
- Yes! Yes Thats him! -I m Oarl Fredrcksen.
我和我妻子都是你的铁杆粉丝
My wfe and I, we were your b ggest fans.
噢 品味不错
Oh we  You're a man of good taste
好了 你们肯定累了 饿吗?
Now, you must be tired Hungry?
Uh- huh
好了 听着 各位!
Now, attent on, everyone!
这些人不再是入侵者! 他们是我们的座上宾
These people are no longer intruders! They are our guests
跟我来 我挺喜欢你
Follow me I like you temporarily
你闻起来确实像李子
You do sme like prunes
哇!
Whoa!
我不会咬你
I wi not bite you
那小邮差闻上去像巧克力
The small mailman smells I ke chocolate
我为狗狗的行径道歉
I'm sorry about the dogs
- 希望他们没有过分粗鲁 - 我们没有
-Hope they weren t too rough on you - We werent
把你的飞屋栓在我的旁边吧
Go ahead and moor your airsh p rght next to mine
我们真的要进入"冒险精神"号?
We're not actua ly going ins de the Spirit of Adventure itself?
噢
Oh...
你愿意吗?
Would you like to?
荣幸至极
Wou d I?
稍等一下 蒙兹先生
Wait up Mr Muntz
我的天呐
Jiminy Cricket
- 你不行 - 我们拿道格怎么办?
- Not you - What do we do with Dug?
他跟丢了大鸟 给他戴耻辱罩
He has lost the bird Put him in the Cone of Shame
我不喜欢耻辱罩
I do not ike the Cone of Shame.
大部分的藏品都被 世界一流的博物馆收藏了
Well, most of the col ection is housed n the world's top museums,
纽约 慕尼黑 伦敦 当然 我把最好的留给自己
New York, Mun ch London Of course I kept the best for myself.
你居然有这么多! 瞧瞧啊!
Did you ever! Will you look at that?
那是重脚兽
Oh, yes, the Arsinoitherium
我刷牙的时候 那个野兽来攻击我
Beast charged while I was brushing my teeth.
我用剃须刀把它制服了
Used my shav ng k t to brng him down
噢 真是吃惊
Oh yeah Well, surprise me
那时候 能把它从埃塞俄比亚 带出来的唯一方法
Only way to get it out of Ethiopia at the time
就是谎称它是牙科器具
was to have it declared as denta equipment.
老天! 索马里巨型豹龟!
Oh, my gosh! The g ant Somalian leopard torto se!
你认出来了 真是佩服
Oh you recognize it I'm impressed
那可是段有趣的经历
That's an nteresting story there
选得好
Exce ent choice
是我和罗斯福探险的时候找到的
I found it on safari with Roosevelt
我们养成了晚上玩纸牌的习惯
He and I fe into a habit of playing g n rummy n the evenings,
他居然作弊!
and did he cheat!
哦 他可真烂!
Oh he was horrible
主人 晚餐准备好了
Master, dinner is ready
哦 翻译器坏了
Oh dear Broken translator
电线又松了 好了 伙计
It's that loose wire again There you go, big fe a.
谢谢 主人
Thank you, Master
我喜欢它刚才的声音
I liked his other voice
晚餐好了 这边请
Well, d nner s served Right this way
美国现在咋样了啊?
So, how are th ngs stateside, huh?
好几次都想回去了
Almost tempted to go back a few times,
但我在这里还有未完成的工作
but I have unfnished work here
但愿你们都饿了
Please I hope you're hungry,
因为老五是我最好的厨师
because Epsilon is the fnest chef lve ever had
老五 你又做了这道菜!
Oh Epsi on, you've done t again!
好耶!
Yes!
嘿嘿!
Hey Hey!
哦 爱丽肯定会喜欢这些的
Oh my Ellie wouldve loved a I this
因为你 她才有了这个梦想
You know its because of you she had this dream
来到这里 住在天堂瀑布边上
to come down here and ve by Paradise Falls.
真是荣幸 现在你做到了
I'm honored And now you've made it
不会打扰你吧? 我不喜欢麻烦人
You're sure were not a bother? I'd hate to impose
不不 有客人来真好 这才算是个宴请嘛
No, no Its a pleasure to have guests, a real treat
- 宴请 哪有宴请! - 宴请
- Treat Where's the treat! - Treat
不不 安静! 都给我安静
No, no Quiet! Calm down, ca m down
- 我要好吃的! 我要好吃的! - 嘿!
- I want a treat! I want a treat! - Hey!
我真不应该用那个词
I shouldn t have used that word
有朋自远方来 不亦乐乎
Having guests s a delight
经常有小偷来偷我东西
More often I get th eves come to steal whats rightfully mine.
不!
No!
他们说我是骗子
They ca led me a fraud those
但只要我把这东西带回去 我就能为自己正名了
But once I br ng back this creature, my name wil be cleared
漂亮吧?
Beautiful, sn t it?
我花了一生来找它
I've spent a lifetime tracking it
有时候 追着追着 几年就过去了
Sometimes years go by between sightings
我试过用烟把它从窝里熏出来
Ive tried to smoke it out of that death y abyr nth where it ives.
但之后人也就进不去了
You can't go in after it
一旦进去 就出不来了
Once in, there's no way out
好多狗都死了
I've lost so many dogs
可现在那些恶棍又跑来 说什么那只鸟是他们的
And here they come, these bandits, and think the bird is theirs to take.
很快他们就会发现 这座山可是非常危险的
But they soon find that th s mountain is a very dangerous p ace
嘿 那个好像凯文
Hey, that looks like Kevin
- 凯文? - 是啊 那只大鸟是我的新宠物
- Kevin? -Yeah, that s my new giant bird pet.
我训练它跟着我们
I trained it to follow us
跟着你们? 不可能 怎么练法?
Fol ow you? It's impossible How?
- 它喜欢吃巧克力 - 巧克力?
-She ikes chocolate - Chocolate?
我把自己的巧克力给她吃 它超爱吃的
Yeah I gave hersome of my chocolate She goes gaga for it.
可是它跑了 已经不见了
But it ran off It's gone now
卡尔 那些路过这里的人
You know Carl, these peop e who pass through here,
总是会说些好听的故事
they all tel pretty good stories
一个测绘员绘制了一张地图
A surveyor making a map
一个植物学家将各种植物分类
A botanist cata oguing plants
一个老头乘着自己的屋子 来到天堂瀑布
An old man taking his house to Paradise Fa Is
这可是最动听的一个了 我都等不及要听它的结局了
I mean that's the best one yet I cant wait to hear how it ends
真是个愉快的夜晚 但是我们必须得走了
Well, t's been a wonderfu evening, but we better be go ng.
你们不能走
Oh you're not leaving
我们不想利用你的热情好客
We don t want to take advantage of your hosp tality
- 过来 罗素 - 可我们还没吃甜点呢
- Come on, Russel -But we haven't even had dessert yet
孩子说得对 你们还没吃甜点
The boy's rght You haven't had dessert
老五做的樱桃派可好吃了
Eps on here makes a del cious cherries jubilee.
我坚决要求你们留下来
Oh you really must stay I nsist
我们还有好多要说呢
We have so much more to talk about
凯文?
Kevin?
它在这儿
It's here
抓住他们!
Get them!
- 快点! - 我已经快了!
- Hurry! - I am hurrying!
啊! 他们来了!
Ahhh! They're coming!
主人 来这边
Master over here
向着光走 主人!
Go toward the light, Master!
罗素!
Russe I!
滚回去!
Get back!
快走 主人! 我去拦住那些狗
DUG: Go on, Master! I will stop the dogs
你们这些狗 都给我停下
Stop, you dogs
Whoa!
救命!
Help!
嘎 嘎 啊! 嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw Raar! Caw, caw Raar!
把手给我!
Give me your hand!
抓紧凯文!
Hang on to Kevin!
凯文
Kevin.
不不不 凯文 别动
Oh no no, no Kevin Stay down
她伤得很重 我们能不能帮她回家?
She's hurt real bad Oan't we he p her get home?
好吧 但我们得快点
All right, but we gotta hurry
你们跟丢了他们?
You lost them?
不 是道格干的
No, it was Dug
是的 它跟他们是一伙的 它帮他们逃跑!
Yeah He's with them He helped them escape!
等等
Wait
等一下 道格
Wait a minute Dug
看到什么了?
See anything?
没看见 那群笨狗没来追我们
No My pack s not following us Boy, they are dumb
真是疯了
Th s is crazy
我终于见到了童年时代的偶像 可他却要杀了我们 真是可笑至极!
I fnally meet my childhood hero, and he's trying to kill us. What a joke!
嘿 我知道一个笑话
Hey, I know a joke
一个松鼠爬到树上说
A squirrel walks up to a tree and says,
"我忘了储存橡栗过冬 现在我死了"
''I forgot to store acorns forwinter and now I am dead '
哈!真逗 因为那松鼠真的死了
Ha! It s funny because the squirrel gets dead.
小心 罗素
Careful, Russell
你还好吗 凯文?
You okay, Kevin?
弗雷德里克森先生 你知道吗?
You know what, Mr Fredricksen?
野外跟我想的不太一样
The wi derness isn't qute what I expected.
是吗? 为什么?
Yeah? How so?
太荒芜了
It's kind of wild
我是说 跟我在书上见到的不一样
I mean, t's not how they made t sound n my book.
慢慢习惯吧 孩子
Get used to that, kid
我爸说得可简单了
My dad made t sound so easy
他真的很擅长露营
He's rea ly good at camping
还会用石头取火
and how to make fre from rocks and stuff
以前每次帐篷大会 他都会来
He used to come to al my Sweat Lodge meetings.
之后我们就去Fentons吃冰激凌
And afterwards, we'd go get ice cream at Fentons.
我总是点巧克力的 他点黄油脆饼
I always get choco ate and he gets butter brickle.
然后我们就坐在路边
Then we sit on this one curb right outs de,
我数所有蓝色的车子 他数红色的
and I II count a the blue cars and he counts all the red ones,
谁数的最多就赢了
and whoever gets the most wins
我喜欢那条路
I like that curb
也许听着很无聊
That might sound boring,
但无聊的事却是我最难忘的
but I think the boring stuff is the stuff I rememberthe most
看! 在那边!
Look! There t s!
嘿 孩子 慢点 罗素 站着别动
Hey, kid Hold on, Russell Stand still
瞧那鸟跑得多快 等等 你这只长过头的大母鸡
Look at that bird go Wait up, you overgrown chicken.
去吧 凯文 去找你的宝宝吧!
Thats it Go, Kev n Go find your bab es!
跑啊 凯文 快跑!
Run, Kev n Run!
哦 不!
Oh no!
罗素 把你的刀给我!
Russell, give me your knife!
放开我的鸟!
Get away from my bird!
不!
No!
小心点 我要把它完好无损地带回去
Careful We'll want her in good shape for my return
放开它! 住手!
Let her go! Stop!
凯文!
Kev n!
你把凯文放走了
You gave away Kevin
你把她放走了
You just gave her away
我才不管这些 我可没想到会这样!
Th s is none of my concern I d dn't ask for any of this!
主人 没事的
Master, it's alright
我不是你主人!
I am not your master!
如果你没出现 这一切就不会发生
And if you hadn't have shown up, none of th s would've happened
恶狗! 恶狗!
Bad dog! Bad dog!
现在 不管你要不要帮我
Now, whetheryou assist me or not,
只要我没死 我就要去天堂瀑布
I am go ng to Paradise Falls if it kills me
我不想要这些徽章了
Here I don't want th s anymore
罗素?
Russell?
罗素!
Russe I!
我要去帮凯文 你不去我也要去!
I'm gonna help Kevin, even if you won't!
不要啊 罗素 不!
No, Russel No!
啊?
Huh?
罗素?
Russell?
道格!
Dug!
我藏在你的门廊下 我喜欢你 我能留下吗?
I was h ding underyour porch because I love you Can I stay?
你能不能留下? 当然了 你是我的狗嘛 对不?
Can you stay? Well, you're my dog, aren't you?
我是你的主人
And I'm your master
你是我的主人?
You re my master?
天啊! 天啊!
Oh boy! Oh boy!
好孩子 道格! 你是个好孩子!
Good boy, Dug! You're a good boy!
好咧!
Yes!
别担心 凯文 我会来救
Don't worry, Kevin. I'I save
他们一看到你就会相信我的
And they wouldn't be eve me Just wait tll they get a look at you.
主人?
Master?
- 那个小邮差又回来了 - 什么?
-The sma mai man has returned -What?
放开我
Let me go
你的老朋友在哪?
Wheres yourelderly friend?
他已经不是我朋友了
He's not my friend anymore
你在这里 就说明他也在附近
We , if you're here Fredricksen can't be far behind
你们把凯文藏哪儿了?
Where are you keeping Kevin?
放开我!
Let me go!
想叫就叫吧 小邮差
Scream all you want, small mailman
你的邮差朋友是听不见的
None of your ma man friends can hear you
我要展现野外探险训练的成果!
I'll unleash al my Wi derness Explorertra ning!
老大 弗雷德里克森s回来了
Apha, Fredricksens coming back.
看好那只鸟 如果见到那老头 你知道该怎么做
Guard that bird If you see the old man, you know what to do
喂 你们上哪儿去啊? 我还没说完呢!
Hey, where are you going? I'm not fin shed wth you!
很高兴和你谈话
Nice ta king with you
啊!
Ahhh!
你在哪儿呢 弗雷德里克森?
Where are you, Fredricksen?
罗素!
Russe I!
- 弗雷德里克森先生! - 道格 把房子转过来!
- Mr Fredricksen! -Dug, brng her over!
你回来救凯文啦! 我们去找她吧!
You came back for Kevin! Lets go get her!
我去找凯文 你留在这里
I'm gettng Kevin You stay here
可我想帮你
But I wanna help
我不需要你帮
I don't want your help
你安全就好
I want you safe
我们怎么绕过这些狗?
How do we get past these dogs?
这儿!
Point!
凯文
Kevin
别担心 凯文 我们马上就到
Don't worry Kev n We're on ourway
别让任何人穿过这些门
Allow no one to be entering through these doors.
看好那只鸟 这是我的命令
Guard wel that b rd, my minions
现在我们该怎么办 道格?
What do we do now Dug?
谁想要球?
Who wants the ball?
- 我 我要! - 我要!
- Me I want it! - Me I do!
- 我要那个球! - 给我!
- I want the ba I! - Give it to me!
那就拿去吧!
Then go get it!
我要先到那儿!
I'm gonna get there first!
拿到球了!
Gett ng the ball!
我拿到了!
I got it!
Uh-oh
对不起 凯文 现在就把你救出去
I'm sorry, Kevin Let's get you out of here.
主人 他跑了! 那个老头!
Master He's gone! The old man!
他在这里!
He's here!
- 他带走了那只鸟! - 那只鸟不见了
- He's got the bird! - The bird's gone
安静 一个一个说!
Calm down One at a time!
我 要 帮 忙!
I want to help!
哈哈!
Ha- ha!
- 他在D厅! - 他在C厅!
- He's in Hall D! - He's in Hall C!
是那个老头!
It's the old man!
有谁知道他们在哪儿?
Does anyone know where they are?
灰狗队长? 把房子撞下来
Gray Leader? Take down the house
灰狗队长 到位
Gray Leader checking in
灰狗二号 到位
Gray Two, checking in
灰狗三号 到位
Gray Three, checking in
锁定目标
Target sighted
快点 凯文
Come on, Kevin
啊!
Auuggghh!
你们好
Hi.
有什么遗言吗 弗雷德里克森? 说吧!都吐出来吧!
Any last words, Fredricksen? Come on! Spit it out!
- 快走 - 够了
-Come on -Enough
我要把那只鸟带回去 不管死活
I am taking that b rd back with me Alive or dead
快走 凯文
Come on, Kevin
这下可是正合我意啊 道格
I wi I have many enjoyments from what I am about to do, Dug.
它戴着耻辱罩!
He wears the Cone of Shame!
什么? 别在那傻站着 进攻!
What? Do not just continue sitting Attack.!
不不! 别笑了! 把这玩意拿下来!
No, no! Stop your laughing! Get thls off of me!
听着 你们这些狗 坐下!
Listen, you dog Sit!
是 老大
Yes, Alpha
老大? 我不是老大 它才是
Apha? I am not Alpha He is
哦!
Oh!
我做不到
I can't do it
- 罗素! - 啊?
-Russe I! -Huh?
嘎 嘎 啊! 嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw Raar! Caw, caw! Raar
你让弗雷德里克森先生落单了!
You leave Mr Fredrcksen alone!
嘿 是松鼠!
Hey, squirrel!
松鼠? 在哪儿? 哪里? 哪里?
Squirrel? Where? Where? Where?
松鼠在哪儿?
Where's the squirrel?
我讨厌松鼠
I hate squirrels
道格!
Dug!
主人!
Master!
罗素! 在这儿 快走!
Russell! Over here Let's go!
弗雷德里克森先生!
Mr Fredricksen!
快跑 凯文!
Go on, Kevin!
不!
No!
罗素! 快出来!
Russell! Get out of there!
不! 离他们远点!
No Leave them alone!
罗素 抓住凯文! 别松手!
Russell, hang on to Kevin! Don't let go of her
凯文! 巧克力!
Kevin! Chocolate!
酷毙了!
That was cool!
别转来转去的 孩子! 慢点 罗素
Don't jerk around so much kid! Easy Russe I
好高 都快吓死我了
Oh, I am ready to not be up high
真为你的房子难过 弗雷德里克森先生
Sorry about your house, Mr Fredricksen
只是座房子而已
You know, its just a house
瞧瞧 你多可爱啊
Look at you You're so soft
嗷!
Aw!
我要是能养一个就好了
I w sh I could keep one
我的手杖呢? 刚刚还在这儿呢
Wheres my cane? ljust had it here
算了 你们留着吧 当做我给你们的礼物好了
You know what? Keep them A ittle gift from me to you
再见 凯文!
Bye Kevin!
准备好没?
Ready?
好了
Ready
根据收集到的徽章
And by receiving their badges,
以下探险者将升级为高级探险者
the following Explorers will graduate to Senior xplorers.
为表彰其卓越的山地知识 祝贺你 吉米
For Extreme Mountaineering Lore Congratulations, Jimmy.
为表彰其野生动物防备技巧 祝贺你 布兰登
For Wild Animal Defensive Arts Congratulations, Brandon.
表彰其帮助老人
For Assistlng the Elderly
罗素 有没有人
Uh, Russe , is there someone that
不好意思 老头来晚了
Excuse me Pardon me Old man coming through.
我是跟他一起的
I'm here for him
祝贺你 罗素 先生
Congratulations, Russel  Sir
罗素 为表彰其帮助老人
Russell, forAssist ng the Elderly
以及远超职责的表现
and for performing above and beyond the call of duty,
我要把我的最高奖章赠与你
I would like to award you the highest honor I can bestow.
爱丽徽章
The Ell e badge
哇
Wow
好了 我想所有人都表彰完毕了
All right, I think that covers everybody
让我们为新当选的
So let's glve a big Explorer call
高级野外探险家欢呼吧
to our brand new Senior Wilderness Explorers.
大家都准备好了吗?
Ready, everybody?
嘎 嘎 啊! 嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw! Raar! Caw, caw! Raar!
- 蓝色的 - 红色的
-Blue one - Red one
- 蓝色的 - 灰色的
- Blue one - Gray one.
- 红色的 - 那是自行车
- Red one - That's a bike
是红色的不就行了?
It's red isnt it?
弗雷德里克森先生 你在作弊
Mr Fredricksen, you re cheating
我可没有 又来个红色的
No I m not Red one
那是消防龙头
That's a fire hydrant
也许我要配副新眼镜了
Maybe I need new g asses
又来辆蓝色的
Another blue one.
飞屋环游记 -=结束=- 谢谢观看
∮Adventure is out there It's heading our way
∮So grab your scarf and goggles Let's fly
∮I've mapped out our journey We're up here to stay
∮A sunset is our home A moonbeam we will own
∮My spirit of adventure is you
∮Freaks of nature span a globe That's too big to deny
∮With canine guards we'll travel there and spit into their eye
∮Bang, bang Once the smoke has cleared
∮After all the crowds have cheered
∮We'll make it a joint venture Before we're in our dentures
∮My spirit of adventure is you
∮Adventure is out there Let's crack some champagne
∮I've hung a hundred heads on my wall
∮To say that I'm traveled is far too mundane
∮Let's grab our aero-fare The high-brows will be there
∮The spirit of adventure is something to indenture
∮My spirit of adventure is you